The
we have thousands of people in this course from all over the world in among these thousands of people
that are in this course.
We could do a survey of what industry do you work in.
Now a lot of people may say they're in the I feel the I.T. industry but I know we have healthcare.
We have manufacturing we have construction probably even industries that you know I know very little
about like a lot of things in life I know very little about.
But these different industries though are application areas.
So let's think about that.
We have people you and others that are from I.T. or construction or healthcare or whatever that may
be how can project management be applied to all of these different areas.
Because a project is a project whether we're talking about building the pyramids way back in time or
we're talking about building a skyscraper in your city three years from now a project is a project the
principles of project management can span all application areas and application area.
It's just a way of describing your industry.
So construction health care I.T. manufacturing government whatever the case may be a project is a project
regardless of the discipline that you operate in.
So it's a really important concept here that we are might have some nuances and some variance between
how you manage a project and how you do it in health care but the generally accepted practices are universal
that in I.T. or a government project or healthcare or construction we always do initiation.
We always plan we execute.
We monitor and control and we close.
I think that's one of the beautiful things about project management is that it's a universal approach
that it allows us to speak with the same terminology and the concepts are the same even though the underlying
application area is obviously different.
Like I know very little about construction and I know I use that as an example lot.
And for new construction people out there are laughing at me or maybe others are laughing at me too.
But I know like that much about construction but the concepts the same in construction or in I.T. or
health care.
So the concepts are what we're focused on in this course not the application area.
So when you go to pass your exam they're not going to ask you questions about you're doing a project
in I.T..
So how would you address an I.T. risk that you know I don't I don't need to know anything about I.T.
to answer the concept of project management that the concepts are universal.
And so when it comes to application areas on your exam don't don't get caught up on that.
Don't let that worry you regardless of what discipline you're from.
The concepts are universal with all of us that are project managers.
All right so be confident.
Keep moving forward.
I'll see you in the next lecture.